

# **SUMMARY**

Visual storyteller, strategic creative, and empathetic advocate of engaging user-centered experiences that align with business goals.

Perceptive and adaptable ENTP-A (Myers-Briggs) leveraging almost 20-yrs of work history in multiple industries and roles in the USA and Asia. Analytical problem-solver with a global perspective.

## **DESIGN PROCESS**

Interviews
Surveys
Competitive analysis
User research
Field study
Personas
Info architecture
Flow diagrams
Sketches
Wireframing
Rapid prototyping
Usability testing
Heuristic evaluation

# **TOOLS**

Figma
Sketch
Invision
Adobe CC
Axure RP
UsabilityHub
UserTesting
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Github
G-Suite

# LANGUAGE

Mandarin Chinese

# **RECENT PROJECTS**

#### WHAT DO YOU MEME?TM MOBILE GAME | view case study

Convert a popular tabletop game for adults into a mobile game. Techniques used: online surveys, field study (observe real-time game play), contextual inquiry, card sorting, storyboarding, A/B testing, moderated usability testing. Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Figma, UsabilityHub, Loom, YouTube.

## **BOXLY** | view case study

Design an SaaS that allows users to collect, store, and share info all from one place. Techniques used: online surveys, user stories, user flows, A/B testing, unmoderated usability testing (wireframes & mockups). Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Draw.io, Balsamiq, Sketch, InVision, UserTesting.

### JW PORTFOLIO | view case study

Hand code a responsive portfolio website (drawing inspiration from Lynn Fisher, Jen Simmons, and CSS Zen Garden) and host it on GitHub Pages. Tools include Figma, UsabilityHub, Dreamweaver, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Github.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **UX DESIGN APPRENTICE | BLOC.IO | Remote**

2018

Complete an **8-mth apprenticeship** under an experienced UX professional. Participate in synchronous **daily design critiques** and **weekly group sessions**; collaborate w/ my cohort via Slack; and complete 3 projects.

# PHOTOGRAPHER | JW PHOTOGRAPHY | Los Angeles

2008 - 2018

Notable clients include: Bebe, HauteLook (Nordstrom), Halston, Ozsale.

## **IN-HOUSE PHOTOGRAPHER | FOREVER 21**

2013 - 2017

**Second-in-command** to photography supervisor; **train** new photographers; shoot appealing images that **drive sales**; some duties exceed original job title and description. Demonstrate **corporate diplomacy and collaborate** across departments.

#### WEB PRODUCER | KAC MEDIA | Los Angeles

2010 - 2011

**Produce** content, **research** the story, **write** scripts, conduct **interviews**, create video rough drafts. **Start-up work culture** with small, nimble, and fluid teams. **Wear multiple hats**, assisting as needed in all tasks from pre- to post-production. **Resourceful** within a limited budget.

### SENIOR EDITOR | ENVISION MBA | Taipei, Taiwan

2006 - 2010

Asia's #1 education consultancy tailoring **branding & strategy** for prospective applicants to **top 50 MBA programs** worldwide. Hundreds of **successful student placements at**: INSEAD, HEC Paris, London Business School, Wharton, Sloan, Columbia, Oxford, Haas, and many others.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BLOC.IO | UX DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP**

2018

#### **UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA (USC)**

2006

B.A. in English & Creative Writing / Minor in Music Business